[Music]
You have joined us, Ravi Sharma. When you
travel abroad, it is always
advised to buy travel insurance. Some
people ignore this and
sometimes suffer the consequences.
How important do you think travel
insurance should be?
Especially in India, we see that there is
not much awareness about insurance, so
travel insurance is still
relegated to second or third priority. So,
how important is it and why should it be taken? In what
way would you like to shed light on it?
Look, Vipul, if you look at whenever we
travel abroad, are traveling outside India,
majority of the time you will be
traveling to a country where the
cost of living is higher than India. So,
you will see that in India,
if you talk in dollars, then that
too is their ₹1, which is equal to 82 rupees. 82
rupees is being used for this.
If you go without trouble insurance,
then travel insurance is not
taken just because if I lose my passport, then no
one will compensate me.
If I get sick there or there is a theft, it will compensate me. If I get sick there, or have an
accident, or any such need
arises in which
I have to access the health infrastructure there, then
you may have to bear a huge cost.
If you do not take travel insurance,
then to avoid all these expenses,
which is a very small cost, you see,
its cost is sometimes ₹500, ₹300,
₹1200, but it
can save a lot of expenses.
You have said this very important thing that means, to
save a small amount, we often
take a big risk.
What kind of problems and difficulties can arise at any place you are going to,
no one has seen the future. Everyone returns safely after a safe journey,
but if such a situation arises, you should have
a backup plan so that you can
return to your country safely and you do
not have to bear a huge financial burden. The
next important question is that when we
go on a foreign trip and this
insurance that we are taking, what all is
included in it, does it have the same  Loss or
suppose some of our belongings are
damaged or broken, are they
covered as well? What are the things that we
should pay attention to when we are taking cover? If we
look at it, at a broad level, this
is an Overseas Medical Mediclaim policy, so just like we used to take cover for
a space medical college in India earlier,
similarly, you can take
cover for medical expenses while travelling abroad,
but today, many companies have
added many additional benefits to make it more complicated and to leverage it.
We can talk about selected benefits,
one of which is permanent accident
cover or permanent disability. So, if
I meet with an accident while travelling
and
I get disabled due to any reason, then the
insurance company will
cover such events as well. There could be some big expenses
like my belongings getting stolen, my passport getting
stolen, my international driving
license getting stolen, getting lost due to any
reason. Yes, believe me, these are huge expenses. I will tell
you a basic one.  Let me give you an
example, I was travelling with you, my friend.
One of the people who was with us lost his passport, which was
around Rs 120,000.
Now multiply that to see
how expensive a little carelessness can be. Generally, the
total travel budget is Rs 2.5 lakhs
and a little carelessness on your part can
add so much expense to your expenses. So, loss of passport,
theft of luggage, personal accident,
disability, all these additional
features are covered in a travel
insurance policy. Let's consider
Mediclaim, the biggest purpose of taking it is that if
I need to access the health infrastructure of the country in any way, or if I need to go to a
hospital, then
I have a policy which will provide me
cashless treatment, which will help me in getting good
treatment without any
financial burden.
Tell me an important thing, but along with all this, I would
also like to tell you that there are some places, there are
some countries where when
you apply for a visa, this is
already there, that is, this  It is compulsory to have
travel insurance.
If you are getting a visa, it
means you have terrorist insurance. Now,
which are these countries and
what is the thinking behind this condition? Is this thinking so that
people who have come have to pay more? Is there any
reason behind this?
You asked a very important question that
travel insurance is expensive in many countries.
So before going into this, I would
like to tell you that there are 37 countries
in this world where you cannot apply for a visa
without travel insurance. On a
broad level, these countries are Western
countries like European countries like
UK. There are some bad countries too. What happens here is that the
government of these countries
believes that if any
citizen is coming to their country, he is their
asset and if any kind of
mistake happens regarding medical treatment, then it becomes the
responsibility of the government to provide them
good treatment and provide them with
accessibility through
health trust, which is this.  They would not
want it at all, so it is obvious that in many
countries where it is considered
that it is the government's liability, the
local citizens or people coming from outside have taken
travel insurance along with the visa in their countries,
so if you apply for a visa, you will have to
attach a travel insurance policy along with it, only then
they will prove your visa and consider the
application, advise that
it is of the state of which they will reject it,
one thing you told that you will get the benefit of all the things from help of uncle to
loss of luggage to medical facility there, will all the
benefits be available in one insurance or
while taking the insurance one has to keep in mind
what things are being covered in it and what is
not, so
what things should be focused on while taking travel insurance,
see exactly what happens that when you go to
take a policy, these other
benefits reduce like an all around feature,
so whenever you are applying for travel insurance,
my advice to
your users or your
audience will be that you should first take a small
browser once and  It comes to what is covered in the
policy, you can review it on one page,
so I can remove many things
from the policy, so if I feel
that my personal accident cover should
not be of Rs 50,000, it should be only Rs 10,000, then
my premium should be a little less, I
feel that Rs 10,000 is too less here, I
want it for Rs 10000, so these advanced features can be increased or decreased, if there is
any
travel insurance policy, then my advice would be that
you should
not buy your travel insurance plan just by looking at the premium, you should
first do a sufficient research, do the background,
what all features are covered and
if all those features suit you, then
you should buy that policy because the price gap between a low
benefit policy and a high benefit
policy is
not very much, this gap will be from Rs 300 to
maximum Rs 3000, there is
not a bigger gap than this, antenna, I
buy it for my parents, whom  It is
already pre-existing, that is a different
subject but maximum you will find that there is
not much gap, so I think
₹300, ₹400 should
not matter, especially I have an
international travel plan of Rs 11 lakh [
Music]
[Music]